The image data from the simulator
シミュレーターからのイメージデータは
is going to be much easier to work with on a GPU
CPUよりGPUで操作する方が
than on a CPU.
はるかに容易になります
So I've launched an AWS EC2 instance with an attached GPU.
そこで GPUをアタッチしてAWS EC2インスタンスを起動しました
And I'm going to train the network there.
そこでネットワークをトレーニングします
I'll use SCP to copy the data up to the EC2 instance,
SCPを使用してデータをEC2インスタンスにコピーし
and then extract the data there.
そこでデータを抽出します
Next, I'll use Python CSV library to read and store
次にPython CSVライブラリーを使用して
the lines from the drivinglog.csv file, then,
drivinglog.csvファイルから行を読み取って保存し
for each line, I'll extract the path to the camera image.
行ごとにカメラ画像へのパスを抽出します
But remember that path was recorded on my local machine.
しかしパスはローカルマシンに記録されています
And now I'm on the AWS instance.
今度はAWSインスタンスを使っています
So I'll need to update the path so it's valid here
そこでパスを更新して
on the AWS instance.
AWSインスタンスで有効にする必要があります
An easy way to update the path is
パスを更新する簡単な方法は
to split the path on its slashes,
パスをスラッシュで分割し
and then extract the final token, which
最後のトークンを抽出します
will be the file name.
これがファイル名になります
Then, I can add that file name to the end
こうすると そのファイル名をAWSインスタンス上の
of the path to the image directory
画像ディレクトリへのパスの
here on my AWS instance.
最後に追加できます
Once I have the current path, I can
現在パスができたら
use OpenCV to load the image.
OpenCVを使用して画像を読み込むことができます
And once I've loaded the image, I
そして 画像を読み込んだら
can append it to my list of images.
それを画像リストに追加できます
I can do something similar for the steering measurements,
出力ラベルとして役立つステアリング角の
which will serve as my output labels.
測定値に対しても同様のことができます
It's actually going to be easier to load this steering
実際 このステアリング測定を読み込むのは簡単です
measurements, because there are no paths or images to handle.
処理しなければならないパスや画像はないからです
I simply extract the fourth token from the CSV line,
CSV行から4番目のトークンを抽出して
and then cast it as a float.
浮動小数点としてキャストするだけです
That gives me the steering measurement
これでこのポイントのステアリング角の測定値が
for this point in time.
わかります
Then, I append that measurement to the larger measurements
次に、その測定値をより大きな測定配列に追加します
array, just like I did for the image.
画像と同じように
Now that I've loaded the images and steering measurements,
画像とステアリング測定を読み込んだので
I'm going to convert them to NumPy arrays,
これらをNumPy配列に変換します
since that's the format Keras requires.
それがKerasに必要な形式だからです
Next, I'm going to build the most basic neural network
次に 可能な限り最も基本的なニューラルネットワークを構築して
possible, just to verify that everything is working.
すべてが機能していることを確認します
This network is just going to be a flattened image connected
このネットワークは1つの出力ノードに接続された
to a single output node.
フラット化されたイメージになります
This single output node will predict
この単一の出力ノードは
my steering angle, which makes this a regression network.
ステアリング角度を予測し それがこの回帰ネットワークを作ります
For a classification network I might
分類ネットワークの場合は
apply a softmax activation function to the output layer.
softmaxアクティベーション関数を出力層に適用します
But in a regression network like this,
しかし このような回帰ネットワークでは
I just want the single output node to directly predict
単一の出力ノードで
the steering measurement.
ステアリング角度を直接予測したいだけです
So I won't apply an activation function here.
そのため ここではアクティベーション関数を適用しません
With the network constructed, I'll compile the model.
ネットワークが構築できたので モデルをコンパイルします
For the loss function, I'll use mean squared error, or MSE.
損失関数として平均二乗誤差 すなわちMSEを使用します
This is different than the cross-entropy function
これは以前使用した
we've used in the past, again because this
クロスエントロピー関数とは違い また これは
is a regression network instead of a classification network.
分類ネットワークではなく回帰ネットワークだからです
What I want to do is minimize the error between the steering
やりたいことは、ネットワークが予測するステアリング角の測定値と
measurement that the network predicts and the ground
検証データの測定値の間の誤差を
truth steering measurement.
最小化することです
Mean squared error is a good loss function for this.
平均二乗誤差は これに適した損失関数です
Once the model is compiled, I'll train it with the feature
モデルがコンパイルできたら 今構築した機能および
and label arrays I just built. I'll also shuffle the data
ラベルでトレーニングします  またデータをシャッフルして
and split off 20% of the data to use for a validation set.
データの20％を切り離して 評価セットとして使用します
Finally, I'm going to save the trained model, so that later I
最後にトレーニング済みのモデルを保存して 後で
can download it onto my local machine,
ローカルマシンにダウンロードして
and see if it works for driving the simulator.
シミュレーターの運転に使えるかどうか確認します
Let's train the model and see how it goes.
モデルをトレーニングしてみましょう
By default, Keras trains for 10 epoches.
デフォルトでは Kerasは10エポックの間トレーニングします
And I can see that the validation loss
最初の7エポックで
decreases for the first 7 epoches,
検証損失の減少を見てから
and then starts climbing again.
再開できます
This is a sign that maybe I'm overfitting the training data.
これは おそらくトレーニングデータをオーバーフィッティングしているサインです
Now it looks a little better.
これで少しは良くなりましたね
Now, the validation loss decreases for almost all
今度は検証損失がエポックのほぼすべてで
of the epoches.
減少しています
Next, I'll download this model to my local machine,
次にこのモデルをローカルマシンにダウンロードして
and see how well it drives the car in the simulator.
シミュレーターでうまく運転できるか確認します